Dhimitër Gëro

Rr. Lidhja e Prizrenit, Tirana, AL 1001 +355 69 430 3737 | dhimitergero@gmail.com

PROFILE

Financial Consultant working in Consultancy Services for *more than 4 years*. Integrated background in *Accounting and Finance* with multi-faceted experience in diverse industries. *Digital Enthusiast* interested in new technologies, with a recent focus on learning *Python and Tableau*. Seeking challenges with a disruptive focus on Finance and Business Transformation. Always committed to self-improvement, results—oriented mindset and highly curious about new business frontiers. Proactive and supportive toward colleagues. Business proficiency in English and Italian.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Data Management Associate (6 months contract)

AON Plc. – Commercial Risk Global Claims Dept.

Chicago, Illinois Aug 2021 – Feb 2022

- · Support the Commercial Risk Global claims Dept. with process improvements, data analysis and manipulation, reporting.
- Involved within a special migration project called 'Claims Resolution Platform' while assisting project managers with data migration activities and change request management with external vendor.
- Coordinate and manage communication with global Aon country leaders regarding specific country related claim system requirements.

Financial Data Engineer

Cardo AI - Securitization Project

Tirana, Albania Aug 2020 – Aug 2021

- Support a portfolio of 6 SPV, more than 500 thsd loans for a total of 1 billion EUR in outstanding balances (SME loan, Public Administration Contracts, Trade Receivables).
- Analysis and treatment of raw data to re-arrange them into robust and structured financial models, tailored for each client.
- Responsible for monitoring a team of three developers (Backend & Frontend), ensure accuracy and testing before client deliveries.
- Create detailed business analysis and proposing functional solutions with an eye on technical opportunities and business requests.

Financial Advisory Services Associate

Deloitte Albania & Kosovo – M&A Project Dept.

Tirana, Albania Nov 2019 – Jun 2020

- Performed in-depth analysis of Target's Financial Statements, with the final focus on generating the right acquisition price of the Target entity (EBITDA adjustment, PPE valuation, Net Debt calculation).
- Partnered with Deloitte Italy FAS Department to assist on their projects of Financial Due Diligences and prepare financial summaries of businesses historical performance.
- Prepared both Seller/Buyer Side Pitch Deck presentation for various projects in industry such as: Public Utilities, Manufacturing, and Fashion.

Business Analyst

Adler Consulting – Business Development Dept.

Tirana, Albania

Nov 2018 - Nov 2019

- Performed financial forecasting models (Three Statement model, DCF, Budget) for domestic and Italian companies with the final focus to facilitate their internal and external business efforts.
- Assisted foreign companies with business plan preparation, pitch deck presentation, and domestic market research for relocation and/or expansion purposes.
- Facilitated and obtained SME grants/funding resources (max 100 thsd EUR) for business enlargement and/or financing operations.

Audit Associate

Tirana, Albania

Mazars Albania & Kosovo – Audit Dept.

Oct 2017 – Nov 2018

- Performed general and specific controls to determine the accuracy and completeness of Clients Financial Statements, following National and International Audit Standards.
- Tested and analyzed audit cycles by implementing tailored strategies for each cycle, in coherence with National and International Financial Reporting standards.
- · Reported findings and misstatements regarding operational and administrative processes of companies' workflow.

Dhimitër Gëro

Rr. Lidhja e Prizrenit, Tirana, AL 1001 +355 69 430 3737 | dhimitergero@gmail.com

EDUCATION

Python 360 Certificate

Ongoing

eCornell, Cornell University, New York

Master of Science in Finance

2016 - 2018

the University of Tirana, Faculty of Economics, Tirana

Bachelor of Science in Accounting and Finance

2013 - 2016

the University of Tirana, Faculty of Economics, Tirana

SOFTWARE COMPETENCIES

- Proficient with Microsoft Office Suite
- Basic Knowledge of Python (+100 Verified Learning Hours)
- Basic Knowledge of Tableau
- Normal User of PROFIS Invoice Cycle Italian Accounting Software

AFFILIATIONS, PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES, AWARDS

- Founder of "Urbana", an online platform that renders on-demand, location-based physiotherapy massages.
 (www.urbana.al)
- Local Governance Expert for Friedrich Ebert Stiftung Tirana. (Tenure 2015 2020)
- Initial contributor in forming "Junior Achievement Albania Alumni" and present member.